Robert J. Tabor

Scottsdale, AZ

bobtabor@q.com bobtabor.herokuapp.com

Web Developer

Self-Starter ~ *Passionate* ~ *Energetic* ~ *Positive*

Seasoned, multitalented web developer, with a passion for web design and client satisfaction. Has a sound balance of web design process analysis skills and technical expertise, ensuring thorough understanding of, and proactive management of projects and programs. Extensive experience in problem solving, customer service, testing, communication, and troubleshooting. Builds productive relationships with colleagues, clients and vendors, across all functional and technical disciplines, providing focused project management, and accurate and detailed business and system analyses. Core competencies include:

- Boundary & Benefit Analysis
- User Interface Design
- **Usability Analysis**
- New Technology

Testing

- Functional/Technical Requirements
- Project Management
- Data Management Office Presentations

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Wordpress

Software: Adobe Creative Suite 6 including Photoshop, Sublime Text 3, Notepad ++, Ruby Mine,

PhpStorm

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PHP

CAREER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Self Employed Web Developer

- Learned many different technologies in a short amount of time with no one to report to but myself.
- Understood which tools to use for different situations in order to save time and frustration for both the client and myself.
- Built many useful applications using various techniques that helped to self-educate and accomplish the client's goals.

ITW Building Components Group

- Created training and processes that bridged gaps between customers, software, and engineering.
- Found numerous bugs and solutions in software that saved customers and engineers countless dollars, time, and frustration.
- Became "go to guy" for help and information for many top clients throughout the western United States, including large manufacturers, that helped profit margins for both the clients and ITWBCG.

Page Two Robert Tabor

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Self Employed, Colorado Springs, CO/Scottsdale, AZ

12/2012 – Present

Web Developer

- Learned proper technologies and techniques in order to design and build static websites.
- Learned how to build dynamic websites using database technology and user interactions.
- Applied knowledge to create interesting and functioning applications for potential clients.
- Used graphic programs to create image based and eye appealing web graphics and images.
- Applied research skills to find solutions to problems and functionality using many different tools.
- Volunteered time, knowledge, and advice to charitable groups in order to help them, and to help myself by learning valuable views from a client's prospective.

ITW Building Components Group, Colorado Springs, CO

06/2000 - 10/2011

- Engineer II
- Trained Customers on using software over the phone, internet, and in-person.
- Reported bugs and potential fixes in software to appropriate personnel.
- Reported customer's issues with software and informed them of potential solutions to their problems.
- Participated in meetings to advise managers and co-workers on software fixes and new features that should be added.
- Gave input and ideas for new features, software versions and programs to software and engineering managers.
- Trained co-workers and new employees on software, new versions of software, and solutions to problems that customers reported.

Engineer II (2007-2011) Designer (2002-2007) Jr. Designer (2000-2002)

EDUCATION

Colorado School of Mines, Golden, CO Civil Engineering

Red Rocks Community College, Lakewood, CO Pre-Engineering

PROJECTS

- BobTabor.herokuapp.com (My Personal Site, Ruby on Rails)
- 30andb.com/dodgers (HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, Adobe PhotoShop)
- btfakestore.herokuapp.com (Ruby on Rails, Spree Commerce)
- coloradosportsreport.com (HTML5, CSS3, Adobe PhotoShop, Logo Design)
- 30andb.com/themtngroup (HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Adobe PhotoShop, Logo Design, Web Graphics)
- 30andb.com/themtngroup2 (HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Adobe PhotoShop, Logo Design, Web Graphics, JavaScript)

Robert Tabor Page Three

- 30andb.com/p3 (HTML5, CSS3,PHP, Adobe PhotoShop, Logo Design)
- <u>30andb.com/mbl</u> (HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Adobe PhotoShop, Web Graphics)
- 30andb.com/roseblog (HTML5, CSS3, Adobe PhotoShop, Web Graphics)
- <u>selectbaseballtryouts.herokuapp.com</u> (Ruby on Rails)
- <u>btsimplecms.herokuapp.com</u> (Ruby on Rails)
- btsampleapp.herokuapp.com (Ruby on Rails)
- 30andb.com/mtngroupintro (Gif Animation for The MTN Group)

GOALS

Thank you so much for taking the time to review my resume. I look forward to answering any questions you may have. In conclusion, I would like to state that while I am very proud of my education and experience, I realize that I have a long way to go to achieve my ultimate goals. I look forward to obtaining more knowledge and experience, personal growth, advancement in both the industry and the community, and always trying to become a better person. I'm excited for the challenge, for my future, and for new opportunities. I have gained much experience and knowledge in my career so far, and I still have a tremendous thirst to gain more. I am very dedicated to my profession and my family. Thank you again, and I hope to hear from you soon.